A Guide to the James Branch Cabell Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #5298-d
James Branch Cabell Collection 1894-1937
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
5298-d
ca. 125 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit, [1963 Dec 17]
Item Listing
- Manuscripts
  - Book review of Smirt, 1934 Feb 1; TMsS, 1 p.
    [Envelope addressed to Richard Butler Glaenzer. ]
  - "For final paragraph in book, 'Ah, yes, this love is an illusion,' etc., substitute:....", n.d.; AMs, 1 p.
- Letters
  - James Branch Cabell to Alice Serpell, ca. 1894; ALS, 3 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Alice Serpell, ca. 1894; ALS, 4 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Alice Serpell, [1894 Oct 29]; ALS, 4 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to Alice Serpell, [1894 Nov 9]; ALS, 3 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to Alice Serpell, [1894?] Nov 20; ALS, 4 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to Alice Serpell, 1894 Dec 7; ALS, 4 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Alice Serpell, [1895 Jan 25]; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to Alice Serpell, [1895 Apr 15]; ALS, 3 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Harper & Brothers, 1905 May 10; ALS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Harper & Brothers, 1905 May 30; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Harper & Brothers, 1905 Jun 13; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Harper & Brothers, 1907 Aug 8; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Rice, 1912 May 1; ALS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Alden, 1913 Sep 25; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to McBride, Nast & Co., 1915 Jan 2; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Barrett H.] Clark, 1920 Feb 16; TLS, 1 p.
    (in slipcase)
  - Printed protest in the form of a letter against the suppression of Jurgen, 1920 Feb 23; PL, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Barrett H.] Clark, 1920 Apr 2; TLS, 1 p.
  - John S. Summer to Barrett H. Clark, 1920 Apr 16; TLS, 3 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Barrett H.] Clark, 1920 Apr 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Barrett H. Clark, 1920 Jun 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Barrett H. Clark, 1920 Jun 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Smith, 1920 Aug 24; ALS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Barrett H. Clark, 1920 Sep 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Barrett H. Clark, 1920 Oct 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Barrett H. Clark, 1920 Nov 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Barrett H. Clark, 1920 Nov 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Barrett H. Clark, 1920 Dec 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Saunders, with a small photo of Cabell, 1921 Mar 18; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Barrett H.] Clark, 1921 Jun 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Barrett H.] Clark, 1921 Jul 19; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Ingersoll, 1922 Jan 23; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Barrett H. Clark, 1922 Jul 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Barrett H. Clark, 1923 Jan 20; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Eddy, 1923 Mar 24; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - W. S. Woods to James Branch Cabell, with TLS reply from James Branch Cabell on verso, 1923 Apr 19; TLS, 2 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Holt, 1925 Oct 5; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Harold] Moses, 1927 Jan 1; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Harold] Moses, 1927 Apr 25; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1927 May 19; ALS, 5 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Harold] Moses, 1927 Jun 29; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Harold] Moses, 1927 Aug 18; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1927 Aug 20; ALS, 4 p.
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1927 Sep 17; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1927 Oct 26; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - F[rank] C. Pape to Harold Moses, 1927 Nov 2; APCS
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Jester, 1927 Nov 8; TLS, 1 p.
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1927 Nov 28; ALS, 4 p. w/env and receipt
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Maxwell, 1927 Dec 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1927 Dec 14; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Harold] Moses, 1927 Dec 21; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1928 Jan 12; ALS, 4 p. w/env
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1928 Jan 20; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1928 Mar 11; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Harold] Moses, 1928 Jul 2; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1928 Aug 24; ALS, 4 p. w/env
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1928 Nov 26; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1929 Feb 9; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to the Centaur Book Shop, 1929 May 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1929 Oct 1; ALS, 4 p. w/env
  - Frank C. Pape to Mr. Booth, [1929] Oct 3; ALS, 2 p.
    [enclosing "List of Originals by Frank C. Pape"]
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1930 Jan 7; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1930 Mar 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1930 Jun 11; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1930 Jun 14; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1930 Jun 17; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Toohey, 1930 Jun 19; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1931 Feb 13; TLS, 1 p.
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1931 Mar 5; ALS, 2 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1931 Mar 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [I. R.] Brussel, 1931 Apr 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1931 Jul 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1931 Jul 22; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Centaur Book Shop, 1931 Sep 30; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1931 Oct 3; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1931 Oct 31; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1931 Nov 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1931 Nov 10; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1931 Nov 17; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1931 Dec 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1932 Jan 15; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1932 Jan 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1932 Feb 27; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1932 Mar 4; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [I. R.] Brussell, 1932 Jun 11; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1932 Jun 11; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1932 Sep 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1932 Sep 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1932 Oct 12; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1932 Oct 18; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1932 Oct 22; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1932 Oct 29; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1932 Nov 22; TL, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1932 Dec 29; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to Mr. Mason, 1933 Feb 16; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1933 May 8; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1933 May 20; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1933 Jun 16; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1933 Jun 24; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1933 Jul 1; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1933 Sep 9; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1933 Oct 21; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to the Argus Book Shop, 1933 Dec 29; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Jan 23; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Jan 27; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - Frank C. Pape to [Harold] Moses, 1934 Feb 1; ALS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Feb 6; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Feb 9; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Feb 24; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Mar 6; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Mar 12; TLS, 1 p. w/env
    [Enclosed is a typescript copy, 1934 Mar 9, Lewis Gannett to James Branch Cabell. ]
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Mar 23; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Mar [28]; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Mar 31; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Apr 7; TLS, 1 p.
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Apr 10; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Apr 28; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 May 15; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 May 20; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 May 24; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Richard Butler] Glaenzer, 1934 Jun 10; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Ben] Abramson, 1937 Jul 24; TLS, 1 p. w/env
  - James Branch Cabell to [Ben] Abramson, 1937 Aug 8; TLS, 1 p. w/env
- Miscellaneous
  - Document recording a sale of land by George Reynell of Malston, Devon, to Richard Cabell of Brooke, Devon, 1669; DS
  - Newsclippings re James Branch Cabell, ca. 1926; Clippings
  - Harold Moses to Frank C. Pape, 1927 Nov 2; Receipt
  - Printed circular re: "The Complete Works of Francois Rabelais", n.d.; Circular, 4 p.
  - Envelope in the hand of Frank C. Pape addressed to Harold Moses, Envelope